the CEO of Derebit, where we're going to talk, of course, about the recent acquisition of Derebit
from Coinbase, but also the future of crypto options and crypto derivatives.
Before we kick it off, of course, our regular disclaimers, nothing that we discuss on this show
is investment advice, and virtual assets may lose their value in full or in part and are subject
to extreme volatility. Second, Derebit is a sponsor of my educational content and companies
that I'm involved in, either as an investor, shareholder, or director, as well as other sponsors
of my educational content, could be clients or counterparties of Derebit. Today's also a very
special day with Luke joining us here, because actually we're recording us for the first time
in the Creator's HQ. A new government, Dubai Build Center, we're actually to attract content
creators. Luke, welcome on the show, and we're being the first guest in this creator HQ in this
bull market studio that we have today. Thank you for having me. Indeed, Luke's quite impressive
all the equipment around me. For those who can watch this on YouTube, you guys could see it's
all proper equipment. Everything is green rooms. Again, Dubai has decided that they believe the
future of Hollywood, the Hollywood of the future are content creators, and I have to say this is
they made it extremely easy for people like us to create the content, really, really very smart
strategic move. I'm actually surprised that more countries are doing this, but let's just jump in,
Luke. I want to talk about various topics today with you. Let's start, of course, with the acquisition
of Derebit from Coinbase. Can you maybe share it with me? We obviously also have their headlines
at $2.9 billion. Can you share maybe with us? Why did Coinbase buy Derebit?
Why is the easy question? That's the product shelf. We are the undisputed number one in options.
We've been having that position since we launched in 2016, when no one cared, and the market didn't
exist. Over the years, many competitors started and tried getting our market share and failed.
If you want to establish a full product shelf, including options, you can do two things either
try like the others or buy, and the latter is what they did. Together with Coinbase, we have
a complete product shelf, essentially. Options, futures, perpetuals, and sports. Across the US,
as well as internationally, Derebit and a part of their options and futures offering is only
available internationally, so not for the US yet, who knows over the years. But
for their client base, as well as ours, it's a massive expansion of product reach, essentially.
It's interesting, actually, that I can definitely see from a business perspective,
when they do the buy, build, partner approach, why Derebit was a good buy from that perspective.
They really become the biggest number one crypto options. Are you guys going to change
a name or is too early yet for a conversation? We're trying to find out as well, so I think
it's not completely clear yet. We've built and created quite a lot of brand equity,
the Derebit D and our merchandise, and we're pretty proud of it. On the other hand,
they've done the same with their C, so the question is whether there's a room for two of these
letters, letters, or whether it will be powered by. I don't think they've made up their mind yet,
so I think the good thing is, the transaction hasn't closed yet, but we're two standalone companies
that are trying to get married in a way. This marriage process means a lot of conversations,
technically regulatory-wise, client-wise, Kate will see, email, but also brand the marketing-wise,
real estate, like offices, what are you going to do? All these conversations are happening,
in the first phase, we started on the acquisition itself, due diligence, etc.
Once the deal was signed, you start talking about this kind of stuff, which essentially means
that a lot of it is still out in the open. It's not agreed upon yet, it's to be confirmed.
So how does where you used analogy of marriage? No acquisition is easy. There's always difficulties,
culture, mindset, size. Do you believe you'll be able to preserve as a CO the culture of Derebit?
I mean, you guys were very entrepreneurial over the years, very cutting edge, as you get into
the Coinbase wrapper. I think that's the key question, everyone, especially internally,
wants to address. I think, culture-wise, we are comparable. So we've been around for quite a while,
the same for them. So we are both older exchanges with a crypto-native mindset,
but with people from the traditional space as well. So we have a mix or a hybrid model that we operate.
The way we work, the offices, the remote working, etc., is all comparable. The big difference is that
we do it with 165 people and they almost have 4,000. So when it comes to coverage and the people
involved in a single topic, for us as a handful, that cover one topic, and for them it's a multiple
hands. And it makes sense, of course, their regulatory reach is much bigger. The number of
clients is much bigger. We operate in niche markets, so we have a lot of institutions,
but we have less retail. They also have a lot of institutes, but also millions of retail. So,
of course, the staff can't, needs to be different. But coverage-wise, it remains to be seen how it's
going to work. I think, culturally, the way people operate, the way people work,
it's comparable. So that's a good basis, and now we still have to find out. But I think it looks
promising. Very interesting. How was your personal experience as a CEO? I mean, obviously now we're
seeing the wave of crypto manneh come in. What advice would you have to other CEOs whose companies
are going through an acquisition process that you've learned over the last couple of weeks and months?
It's difficult to get advice, because every situation is unique. I think the first months,
the digital space is the hardest. So the companies, they operate and we operate on
different time zones. So that's one. They are on East Coast, but the big chunk of their staff
is West Coast. We are 12 hours away from West Coast. We are on Dubai, we are in Amsterdam,
we're in Asia. So if you look at the time to talk about topics, whatever, it's difficult to plan,
and it's always at the expense of one side of the equation, typically us.
That's not really true, actually. But they have been very flexible, but it's difficult finding a slot
that works for both sides. The other thing, so that's just operations. The other thing is the extent
of a judicial process. So if you've never gone through it, it's a lot of work. So first it starts
with bankers or the advisors creating the reports, which takes a lot of time. There's months and
months of work. It means that every number has to be verified, has to be accounted for. Why did it
change in March 2020, whatever? And you need to explain and be able to demonstrate full control
of everything you've done over the years and will do. So that takes a lot of time. And then it's
just all that together with operating a linear mean company. So you can be linear mean in your
operational business. But then if you have a big add-on, which you didn't account for,
all of these questions and all of these reports, that's when it becomes difficult. So people feel
stressed slightly, and making that happen is the more difficult. I think, but that doesn't end
inside. So there's not an ongoing thing. There's a clear goal. And once a goal is reached, it's
where we are now. It's about the future. Now we're going to organize that. And that's much easier.
It's always tricky, because like you said, your team has already existing pieces of work to do,
and then this comes on top. And of course, this takes priority over everything else,
takes out the focus. So it's always a perpetual challenge, no pun intended on that, but on
for companies on that perspective. And I can also see why it makes sense for Coinbase to acquire
there. But obviously, like the role the guys play in the derivatives market, in the options
market in particular, it's a very, very interesting acquisition on that side. Let's see how the rest
of the acquisition goals, but also there's so many M&As going on right now in the crypto space,
I think, will be quite interesting to watch. I want to focus, Luke, on what we are seeing
right now on crypto options. I mean, can you give us maybe an update on your side on Durbit?
What are you guys seeing in terms of crypto options right now? Let's say in terms of volumes,
client type, and how did this change compared to a couple of years ago?
So if you look at the market today, look at May, May 2025. So last month, we traded $138 billion
in Notional Tokyo, which is the best month for 2025. And it's just shy of November last year. So
November was our best month ever. So we're really looking at very high elevated volumes. And that's,
I think we're doing pretty well because of our option shell. But I think the overall derivative
space is looking at comparable numbers. So overall, the derivative trading is at very high levels.
If you look at our options shelf, which is what makes us unique, it's about, let's say, 100 billion.
So out of the 138, 140, 100 billion is options. A few years ago, during the
the ETH flippening and those narratives, I'm not sure whether you remember,
but that those moments open interest was approximately even between BTC and ETH and volumes as well.
Now it's completely the other way around. So it's purely focused on BTC and BTC would be,
let's say, 80 billion out of the 100. So 80% would be bitcoin options and not no longer spread across
multiple underlies. We've launched multiple products. So initially, we only had these two.
We expanded with linear options as we call them, use DC based options over underlies like B&B,
XRP, Solana. And we're now looking at expanding the range. We launched Gold, on Pax's Gold.
We expanded the coverage, but still the focus and the entire markets focus and the price focus as
well. So everyone is underperforming if you're not heavyweight or over-allocated towards BTC.
So that's where the focus is. If you look at who's trading, a lot of it is institutional flow.
So if you look at us, we have 80% give or take of the options market, 78, 79 in May, open interest-wise.
The rest of the market is spread across multiple different platforms, including CME, for example,
in the US. But if you look at the US retail market, they don't have X2 to see me,
they trade IBIT options to ETF. So they do pretty well, but not at our expense. That's a nice thing.
So we've kept on growing in dollar terms as well as contract terms. So you have to look at both
metrics to get a fair impression. And we've grown across both. That means that the IBIT
ETF flow that has been unlocked is new flow, which is great. Because that
powers all kinds of trading strategies. If you have access to both, you can up these markets. You
can have different collateral, different. So we accept, for example, UDC, but we accept BTC,
we accept national, we accept lighter, we accept the thinner, we accept yield-bearing collateral,
stablecoin collateral, as well as BTC collateral. The US markets are completely different. They
accept dollars. That's it. So if you're able to play with these differences, there's all kind of
trading strategies that will be a lot generating additional volume. And that's what we see now.
I think the allowing, not only the BTC collateral, which is obviously the origins of
there, but I think letting Tina and other yield-bearing assets, I mean, that was very smart. And I can
see over the next couple of months, and your other exchanges will need to follow what the
therebet has done on that perspective. I think it remains to be very interesting.
You know, I'm always interested in, like, obviously, when it comes to Bitcoin office and
versed options, you know, there's a little nuances when it comes to trading crypto options.
What is the biggest hurdle you're seeing? Let's you mention a big chunk of your clients are
institutional investors. Is it the fact that they don't have the BTC to use as BTC collateral?
Is it that they're not comfortable with the particularities of Bitcoin options? What is the
biggest hurdle you are seeing for these institutional players to come on there a bit and trade crypto
options? It's not only unique for there, but there were, like, a few years ago, there were, like,
these many hurdles. One of them was custody. So they didn't trust exchanges, especially after
problems that occurred. So after FTX, after HEX, et cetera, et cetera,
not your keys, not your go, all of that stuff. So custody was important. So we added multiple
custodians. So I think we have seven by now. So we have, we started with copper, but we have five
blocks of exchange custody. We have fidelity, combining Zodiac, Bitco, Signum, whatever you're
comfortable with, you can choose. And for some people, that means I want a certain part of the
world. I want an Asian one. I want European one, a certain license that, so when you asked me the
question a few years ago, it would have been costly. We've addressed that. Then after FTX, it became
about trust. So are the coins really there, et cetera. That means regulatory, as well as operational
checks, that needs to be some verification of what the exchange claims to do, which meant we
relocated to Dubai, got a viral license for everything we do. So not only sport, but not only drills with
everything, it includes custody, it includes margin, et cetera. We have been either certified,
we're socketed by type one, type two, we have CCSS, which is like private management. We have all
of this financials, the fifth years coming, I think, within a week or two, all of that stuff
is a hurdle for many. So if you go to a big bank broker, asset manager, they will ask all this
stuff. If you don't have it, it simply ends there. You can't convince anyone. It's simply, it's a need.
So we've done all of that. That means we get more and more clients to onboard. We get regulated
clients. We get asset managers. We get firms that focus on this kind of stuff that are onboarding now.
I think it will change after coinbase. So after coinbase, we get a big balance sheet. So some firms
also focus on how big is your balance sheet, how big is the ability to absorb a problem?
Regulatory wise, I think we are expanding as well. So we're filing for mythic licenses in
France at the moment. We're looking at Brazil, we're looking at Asia. Together with coinbase,
we might expedite that role as well. So if a big asset manager from whatever country
requires a local license, it's a no-go area otherwise. You can work with primes, potentially,
that are licensed, but these are key items. So then the last thing is, I think that's what
you alluded to, was the product itself itself. So yes, initially, BTC was the big
unlocker perhaps of assets because if you have 1000 BTC and you want to generate yield,
you have to deploy those BTC somewhere. We're perfect for that. You can use your BTCs and sell
out the money calls, for example. That's what a lot of institutions do. If you go to the CME,
they don't welcome your BTCs. You simply can't deploy them. So we gain by doing so.
But not everyone owns BTC. If you look at the big institutions, they don't want to have and
touch, because it messes up their accounting, their compliance, whatever, all of their
procedures are not done yet. And yes, everyone is trying to do some sandbox model with some
people here, they're allocating a few million dollars. But if you look at the real size, they're
not yet deploying, that means they want to use their dollars preferably or whatever currency they're
so half, or half, let's say part of that community will be able to use Stable. That's why we're launching
linear points. You can use your Stablecoin. That's why we have expanded the cross-clatterable
with Stable. And you can utilize them. But at some points, not all will be willing to do so,
because it's still a Stablecoin. It still requires wallets. It still requires all kinds of operational
stuff that they might not be doing today. So at some point, we also might be looking at use the
which could be covered by Coinbase. So I think doors are opening there.
Now, I can say down the line, even if you're an institutional investor, and forget even BTC,
that's you get comfortable with Stables, the key management, the wallets, the custody,
there's so many complications that often they're not dealing with it right now,
that's why I've listed the USD collateral can help. And how do you see Luke the future of
Deribid when it comes to let's say CME or pure dollar, ratify options? Do you believe these two
roles will evolve independently? You think some of the clients that right now are trading CME will
come into the Deribid world or vice versa? How do you see these two ecosystems evolve, which are
right now, pretty much as you mentioned before, independent of each other?
So CME is massive when it comes to futures. So they are let's say 10 times bigger than the next
guy, and we are pretty big in futures as well. Because if you trade options, you need to have
futures as a hedge. Typically, the data futures are used for that. So if you let's say trade
whatever, the June expiry, you prefer to hedge with the June future instead of the perpetual.
So yes, buying these OKX, et cetera, are big in perpetuals, but typically not to use as a hedge
for open options position, you use futures. So we're pretty big, but CME is much bigger.
If you look at the options side, CME has less than 1% of the May volumes is coming from CME.
So option wise is tiny and we're like massive, let's say 70 times bigger than CME. So will that
go hand in hand? I think we will keep dominating and CME is not the way it reads. What I alluded
to before was IBIT. I think in the U.S. the exes, the institutions can trade it. They can also trade
offshore, a lot of them have offshore. The retail can't. So that's why they trade IBIT options.
The IBIT ecosystem is completely different than ours. So IBIT is a security. It trades like Tesla.
So everyone that has a broker's account, which is millions of people and everyone of those people
that are able to trade options, which is again, millions of people can trade the IBIT options
around. But the big question is can exchanges like us access U.S. liquidity? And that's not
easily solved. So even though there's a different administration, the rules are the rules. So the
CFTC or the SEC are pretty clear what needs to be done and who knows over time together with
Gormis, we can address it. But there's not like something that's instantly available.
No, I think you're right. The analogy I should have used is not CME, but actually IBIT options,
which is a more and it's very interesting how these two operate independently right now.
And you know, Luke, I've always wondered personally, when I look at the crypto options world,
and you know, I've been like you in crypto for a long time now, I'm genuinely surprised the
crypto options world is not bigger. You know, often you look at maybe, you know, one quarter,
two quarters away, you know, compared to TRATFI, which the option rules very, very multiple times
out of spot. What do you think until now, the crypto options world has not been bigger than what
it is today? So if you look at the aggregate of all the drift Australia options is, let's say,
two and a half percent, which is indeed limited. So the rest would be futures and the big chunk is
perpetual. I think the latter is the answer to your question. So if you look at, again,
let's take the US example and people trading Tesla, if they want leverage exposure to Tesla,
that's not much they can do except trading options. But they're pretty well versed in trading
Tesla options. And that's why, let's say, half half of the US options volumes is retail,
because all of them trade Tesla a bit like they would trade perps. But perps are not available or
that that is changing now, but overall, they've never been available. So in the absence of perps,
a lot of people trade options. If you look at the international space where perps are available,
a lot of those people who trade perps simply for leverage exposure, if you want targeted exposure,
you want to trade a certain strike, you want to trade volatility, you want to trade the spread,
the call spread, the vertical, all that stuff, that's what perps never can do. So it's not
perps never replace options. They replace options for a certain group of people.
But the rest of the people are, they will ever always trade options.
Yeah, I see your point, especially if retail investors just once
levered long term position, the perps can be interesting. They're often very easy as
well, right? You don't need much technical knowledge to trade on. How do you see from a
derivative perspective, the future of perps on your platform? You mentioned how you're
expanding the suite of options, you know, not only BTC collateral, but obviously the whole suite of
other collateral that can be used. What about perps? How do you see that mix changing within the
derivative platform over the coming years? I think if you look at our options that will expand.
So we have, let's say for the linear suite, we have four linear now. Let's say we add
five more, let's say six for the sake of the discussion. We would have 10 options, options
in the lines. Typically, if it's not BTE or ETH, you would address more sophisticated traders,
retail traders. So retail trades short of dated expires. They trade tomorrow's expiry. They trade
this Friday's expiry. And if you want to hedge those, you don't necessarily need options or
futures. You want to trade to September expiry. The market makers would hedge preferably using
the September future. But if you trade tomorrow, there's no future that expires tomorrow. They
would trade the perps. But if you look at where an options mark, if you purely focus on options,
what would you need? You need a liquid futures market or perps market for your shorter dated
rings. If you have 10 options in the lines, you need 10 perps. If you, besides your options shelf,
want to focus on your sophisticated traders globally, you can add 10, 20 more perps. But do you want
100 perps? Not necessarily, because you would go to buy this bet. It makes sense on that side.
What are you finding is the biggest challenge as a CEO when he comes with it to client acquisition?
You talk to many institutions you're dealing with, you talk to many, you talk to some of the
retail target you guys have. What do you think is the biggest challenge? Is it, for example,
marketing? Is it regulations? Is it just conflict with the asset class? How do you see that evolving?
I think it's a mix of all, sadly. You started the podcast with all of your warnings, the regulatory
mandatory stuff. We are filing for Miffit license in order to be able to offer our product. Wherever
you're not licensed, you can't offer your product. So your hands are tight when it comes to marketing,
you can't do anything. So we like to offer our products. However, we don't have a standard
product that everyone is interested in. So do we want football shirts and race cars with a
derivative logo? It would look amazing, but the added value wouldn't be high because a lot of the
people interested in those sports or whatever the activity is are not interested in options,
options is a niche product. That's why we like to focus on sophisticated ways,
and those are more difficult to find. So it's a mix of what can you do, what are you permitted to,
but if you are permitted, what is the best way to approach these people? And that's a very
difficult question to answer. So we've been trying over the years many different things,
but there's no clear and simple answer. It's about reputation. It's about quality. It's about
statistics. People that do their homework don't just sign up anywhere with a random click. If they
see a logo, they Google, they check what they find, they look at the statistics. Do these people
actually have the percentages they claim to have, etc. And then it's about quality. If you trade an
option, let's say you traded this number option. And I'm not sure when this show is going to be
out, but let's say six months expiry. That means we are entering a six-month contract.
It's not only a spot rate, it's instant, right? So we trade and you're done. You can move your
coins out and you can eat spot ways. A perpetual trade is often short duration as well. You don't
trade a perpetual for six months. The funding element will kill your piano. So all of these
products are short dated. An options product is a long-term engagement. We margin you today,
and we will margin you tomorrow, and the day after, and the day after.
So this relationship is different. So it's about quality again, in order to find and do marketing,
you market with the stuff you do well. You market your certifications, your market of
the quality you have, your book liquidity. It's very interesting, actually. You mentioned that
the nature of the relationship people are having with exchanges, you're right. I can see that the
duration has a big element, again, from your perspective, you're looking at it. And I have to
say one thing that being just educating people in crypto for a decade now, I have to say, you
guys have a great platform on the educational platform on there. But for people who want to
learn about crypto options, I highly recommend, by the way, I forgot I was calling it. It's called
Derbit Academy. We have multiple things, but it's very good. It can be in the inside brands.
Very, very well done, by the way. Well done to your team. To finish it off, look like,
let's say we have this podcast together in five years. How do you see the crypto derivatives and
option world you think in 2030? If you asked me five years ago, I think I would have
under, or perhaps overstated the success. I think over a longer time,
crypto will be included as a standard asset class, like any asset class. That would definitely happen.
The question is how fast this will happen. So a few years ago, everyone said all the institutions
are coming in 2020 or whatever, 2021. And it didn't happen. So yes, some of them are coming.
And yes, some of them will include crypto in whatever two years from now. You see that the
brand, the brokers, all of them are included. But if you really look under the hood, what are they
including? Can you deposit assets from externally? Often no. Is it real crypto or is it ETF, etc.
So it's small steps. Five years from now, let's say the biggest, the most difficult part would be
the big asset managers and the investment banks will all of them be there five years.
I hope so. That's our game plan. So we focus on the institutions and we're doing whatever we can
to make to prepare for their arrival, so to say. But who knows? I'm a thousand percent
convinced that they will come. The difficulties of time mine.
Yeah, timeline has been tough. I've been wrong multiple times over the years as well on the
timelines. Look to finish it off. There's a tradition, whoever comes on my show, the bell
is with me. I want to ask you quick, quick questions and I need one or two word answers
to these questions. You're ready? Yes. Here we go. Let's kick it off. Look, you're now based in Dubai.
What's your favorite thing about Dubai? The location location. I really, of course, time's
on wisely. Time's on wisely. It's perfect. You can travel. So my family is from Europe.
You can travel to Europe easily. We have a big client base in Asia. You can travel there.
Calling clients is really convenient. I agree. You're originally from Holland. What's your,
what's the one thing you missed the most about Holland? I think it's the range of cheese.
We often have discussions about which country is the best cheese, but the Netherlands is pretty
good in cheese and we have shops everywhere. Really, cheese. I didn't expect that from that
perspective. That's why we love these questions. What's the one thing about the crypto industry
that's keeping you up at night, generally, about the crypto industry that keeps you up at night?
And that's a serious answer. I guess it's security. It's not only physical security for
the team, but also just wallets and hacks and all of that stuff. So you see these nasty stories.
We are pretty convinced that we have like a proper setup, but you never know it's very.
If there's one coin you can hold for the next 10 years outside of Bitcoin, one coin that you
can hold the next 10 years, which, what would it be? Difficult one, um, epsilon. There you go.
If there's one favorite Netflix or YouTube series that you like and you think people should watch,
what is it? I like the Peaky Blinders. Peaky Blind? Yes. A little bit of aggression perhaps
for your audience. Okay. I don't know what it is, but here we go. Um, this is a funny one.
Donald Trump's give you Donald Trump gives you a call and says to join his crypto advisory committee.
What's the one piece of advice you give him? I would advise him to review.
The international, uh, system as an infrastructure, uh, globally and not only the US markets. I think
if you can fix that, not only to Trump, but any country, if you can, if you can be like a key
component for equivalence regulatory wise, et cetera, globally, it would solve those things.
Good point. Another one. If you could go back to school today, what is the one course, I know
you studied at master's university. What, what's the one course you would take back in university?
You wish you had taken knowing what you know now about the future of finance.
I would have loved to know more about coding coding.
Tomorrow you launch a new startup. What is the one other CEO you would love to have as a
co-founder in the crypto space? I think if, if I were to launch something new, I would, um,
I would focus on AI, um, but not necessarily with someone that is already doing it because
that's, that's already a room on the side. I don't have an answer for you in that one, but I would
love to be, um, part of AI converting into like, actual speech and, and, and, and, and
conversation partners and the stuff that you, you're starting to see about is like,
personalities, um, the Amber team did a great job. Not sure whether you've seen that, um, but like
virtual persons that actually have a personality that can talk on your behalf without being programmed
like on the fly. So many amazing things going on outside. Um, what is the one thing that excites,
excites you the most about the crypto industry? I think the one thing that scares most,
excites you. Yeah, but it's, for me, it's the same thing as what scares many is the 27 element.
I think it's amazing if what you can see that, that, that when, when markets are calm, what can
happen in the weekend? Um, I think the 24/7 angle, um, rates like a different mindset for the people,
the team, the operations, the, the way you release stuff, the way you build your platform. It's really
a mind. Um, it's, it's, it's, it's, it's a difficult game to play. The last question to close off this
episode, Luke, the traditional question of whoever comes on my show, if you could have lunch or dinner
with one person that are alive lunch or dinner with one person that are alive, who would you have,
who would you have a lunch or dinner with? Napoleon, really? What's that?
A seizure or whatever someone that has gone with the globe, part of the globe.
The good old, uh, general was a dictator. Here we go. Well, that was, uh, look,
stares. Oh man, if I'm having difficulty after many will have as well, uh, the CEO of Deribet,
hope guys this was a useful episode that talking about the future of Deribet and crypto options.
See all soon for another episode of the future money podcast. If you want to get in touch with
me, other for a sponsorship, speaking engagements or any other questions, you can find the contact
page on my website, HenryArslian.com, H-A-N-R-I, Arslian, A-R-S-L-A-N-I-N. See you guys all soon,
for another episode of the future money podcast.